

# Mohammed Ali Hadi

Master of Information Technology Management

+966 508430836

🔽 mohammed.ali.hadi25@gmail.co

🧎 - Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

www.linkedin.com/in/mohammed-ali-hadi

#### Skills

Programming in multiple programming languages (Java, C#

- C++, Aps.net, SQL Serve, ORACLES, PHP, MySQL, VB.net, JavaScript, Html & CSS & etc.)
- Microsoft SharePoint
- Cloud Computing (VPS & VDS)
- Database Administrators
- Programming Android Apps
- Project Management
- Analysis and design of systems
- Microsoft Office (Word,PowerPoint,

  Excel, MS Project, & etc.)
- ERP (Enterprise Resource

  Planning)
- Quick learning

## Languages

Δrahic

English

### Certification

Project Management Professional (PMP) In the Ultimate Training Center 28 January - 15 February 2017

Managing project using Microsoft Project In the Ultimate Training Center

## Profile

I have more than six years of experience managing information technology and developing systems and Android applications. Through my scientific and practical career, I gained excellent knowledge of information technology systems, software development methodologies, database management, and design, where I developed many systems and Android applications, including an accounting system for auto parts stores, as well as a remote attendance system using GPS and fingerprints on Android mobile devices, among others. I also have substantial experience in Microsoft products, sales, customer relationships, and account management.

### Experience

Senior Sales Engineer Space Secure November 2022 - Now Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

As a senior sales engineer, my responsibilities included the management of cloud computing systems, network linking, marketing of services, providing technical consultations, analyzing requirements, and providing technical support and coordination.

Information Technology Specialist Al-Nagri for Trading & Agencies January 2019 - July 2022

Sana'a, Yemen

As an information technology specialist, my responsibilities included managing and developing systems and databases, supervising their work, and providing technical support to employees.

Developer of Android Applications Itgan Soft June 2018 - November 2018 Sana'a, Yemen

As an Android app developer, my responsibilities included collecting requirements, analyzing, and programming.

Specialist Software Development

MAN Telecom Solutions

August 2016 - April 2018 Sana'a, Yemen

As a specialist in software development, my responsibilities included the software development and management company's network installation and administration, telecom equipment hardware installation, operation and maintenance, project management, and supervision for it.

#### Education

Master of Information Technology Management with an excellent grade of 94%. 2018 - 2022 Sana'a University

Bachelor of Software Engineering with a very good grade of 88.49%. 2012 - 2016
Saba University

# Of my projects

- 1. Remote Attendance System using GPS and fingerprints: It consists of three parts: An android application that uses GPS and fingerprints to attend, and system management was developed using C# and the database SQL Server. It is linked by using a Web Service.
- 2. The Smart Account System for auto parts stores: It is a smart sales and accounting system designed to meet the needs of auto spare parts stores, as it is characterized by a strong structure in the database design that enables it to work effectively and quickly in search and lightness in storing data, as well as having an easy and simple design that is easy to learn and use. The system was developed using C# and SQL Server databases, and database schemas and relationships were designed using Microsoft Visio.
- 3. An Electronic Proxy System: It is a system developed for the organization for financial accounts, developed using C# and SQL Server.